Another Caucasian, Gary.
Right, Dude.
Friends like these,
huh, Gary?
That's right, Dude.
Do you have
A good sarsaparilla?
Bartender:
Sioux city sarsaparilla?
Yeah. That’s a good one.
How you doin'
there, Dude?
Not too good, man.
One of those days, huh?
Yeah.
Well...
A wiser fella than myself
once said,
"Sometimes you eat
the bar and--"
Much obliged.
"And sometimes
the bar, well...
He eats you."
Hmm. That some kind
of eastern thing?
Far from it.
I like your style,
Dude.
Hmm. Well...
I dig your style, too,
man.
You got
a whole cowboy thing going.
Thankie.
There's just one thing,
Dude.
And what's that?
Do you have to use
so many cuss words?
What the fuck
are you talking about?
Ok, Dude,
Have it your way.
Take her easy, Dude.
Yeah. Thanks, man.
Call for you, Dude.
Hello?
Maude: Jeffrey, you have
not gone to the doctor.
Uh, oh, yeah.
no--no, I haven't yet.
Uh--
I'd like to see you
immediately.
Oh?
So you're Lebowski.
Yeah.
Maude has told me
all about you.
She'll be back
in a minute. Sit down.
Do you want a drink?
Yeah, sure.
White Russian.
The bar's over there.
So what do you do,
Lebowski?
Who the fuck are you,
man?
Just a friend
of Maudie's.
Yeah, the friend
with the cleft asshole?
What do you do?
Oh, nothing much.
Maude: Hello, Jeffrey.
Hello.
Yeah, how are you?
Um...
Listen, Maude,
I got to, uh...
Tender my resignation
or whatever,
Because, uh...it
looks like your mother
really was kidnapped
after all.
She most certainly
was not.
Hey, man, why
don't you fucking...
Listen occasionally?
You might
learn something.
Now, I got--
Please don't call her
my mother.
She's most definitely
the perpetrator
and not the victim.
I'm telling you, I got
pretty definitive evidence--
From who?
From the main guy--
Oolie.
Oolie Coco?
Her co-star in
the beaver picture?
Beaver?
you mean vagina--
I mean,
you know the guy?
I might have introduced them
for all I know.
Do you remember Oolie?
Hmm.
He's a musician. Used
to have a group--Autobahn.
Look in my LP's.
They released one album
in the late seventies.
Their music is sort of
a--ugh--technopop.
So he's pretending to be
the abductor?
Well, yeah.
Look, Jeffrey, you don't
really kidnap someone
you're acquainted with.
The whole idea
is that the hostage can't
be able to identify you
after you've let them go.
I know that.
What the fuck
is with this guy?
Who is he?
Knox Harrington.
The video artist.
So Oolie
has the money?
Well...
Uh, no, not exactly.
Uh...
This is a very
complicated case, Maude.
A lot of ins,
a lot of outs,
a lot of what-have-yous,
and, uh,
a lot of, uh, strands
to keep in my head, man.
A lot of strands
in old Duder's head.
Hello?
If Oolie doesn't have it,
then who does?
Ha ha ha ha! It's Sandra,
about the Bearnali.
Uh, look,
I have to take this.
Do you still have
that doctor's number?
Oh. No, really. It's
not even bruised anymore.
Oh, please, Jeffrey,
I don't want
to be responsible
For any delayed
after-effects.
After-effects?
Maude: See, see.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Could you slide
your shorts down,
Mr. Lebowski, please?
Hmm?
No. No, man.
She hit me right here.
I understand.
Could you slide
your shorts down, please?
# Just got home
from Illinois #
# Lock the front door,
oh, boy #
# Got to sit down,
take a rest on the porch #
# Imagination sets in #
# Pretty soon I’m singin' #
# Doo doo doo #
# Lookin' out my back door #
# There's a giant
doing cartwheels #
# A statue
wearin' high heels #
# Look at all
the happy creatures #
# Dancin' on the lawn #
# A dinosaur Victrola #
# Listenin' to Buck Owens #
# Doo doo doo #
# Lookin' out my back door #
Ow! Ooh! Ooh!
# Tambourines and elephants
are playing in the band #
# Wondrous apparition #
# Provided by magician #
# Doo doo doo #
# Lookin' out my back door #
# Tambourines
and elephants #
# Are playing in the band #
# Won't you take a ride
on the flyin' spoon? #
# Doo doo doo #
# Bother me tomorrow #
# Today I’ll buy
no sorrows #
# Doo doo doo #
# Lookin' out my back door #
He lives
in north Hollywood,
on Radford, near
the in-n-out burger.
The in-n-out burger's
on Camrose.
Near
the in-n-out burger.
Those are good burgers,
Walter.
Shut the fuck up,
Donny.
The kid is in
ninth grade, Dude,
And his father is--
Are you ready for this?
His father is
Arthur Digby Sellers.
Who the fuck is that?
Huh?
Who the fuck is
Arthur Digby Sellers?
Ever heard of a little show
called branded, Dude?
Yes, I know--
All but one man died
there at bitter creek?
I know the fucking show,
Walter. So what?
Fucking Arthur Digby Sellers
wrote 156 episodes, Dude.
Huh.
The bulk
of the series.
Oh.
Not exactly
a lightweight.
No.
And yet his son
is a fucking dunce.
Heh.
Anyway, we'll go there
after the what-have-you,
we'll brace the kid,
should be a pushover.
We'll be near
the in-n-out burger.
Shut the fuck up,
Donny!
We'll go out there,
we'll brace the kid,
He should be a pushover.
We'll get that fucking
$1 million back--
If he hasn't spent it
already.
A million fucking clams.
And yes, we'll be near
the, uh...
In-n-out.
Hey, shh! Shh!
Some burgers,
some beers,
a few laughs.
Our fucking troubles
are over, Dude.
Oh, fuck me, man!
That kid's already spent
all the money, man!
New 'vette?
Hardly, Dude.
I'd say he still has
960, $970,000 left,
depending on the options.
Wait in the car, Donny.
Woman: Yes?
Pilar?
My name
is Walter Sobchak.
This is my associate
Jeffrey Lebowski.
Um, we came to talk
about little Larry.
May we come in?
Pilar: Yes, yes.
Thank you.
That's him, Dude.
And a good day to you,
Sir!
Uh, sit down, please.
Larry, sweetie,
that man is here!
Is he...
Does he still write?
Oh, no, no.
He has health problems.
Uh-huh.
Uh, sir, I just
want to say, uh...
That we're both,
on a personal level...
Really enormous fans.
Branded, especially
the early episodes,
was truly a source
of inspiration--
Pilar:
Sweetie, sit down!
Uh, this man
is the police.
Oh, no, ma'am,
we didn't want
to give the impression
that we were police
exactly.
We're hoping
it won't be necessary
to call the police.
But that's up
to little Larry here.
Isn't it, Larry?
Is this your homework,
Larry?
Look, man--
Dude, please.
Is this your homework,
Larry?
Just ask him
about the car, man.
Is this yours, Larry?
Is this your homework,
Larry?
Is that your car
out front?
Is this your homework,
Larry?
We know it's
his fucking homework!
Where's the fucking money,
you little brat?
Look, Larry...
Have you ever heard
of Vietnam?
You're entering
a world of pain, son.
we know that this is
your homework.
We know that you stole
the car.
And the fucking money!
And the fucking money.
And we know that this
is your homework.
We're gonna cut
your dick off, Larry.
You're killing
your father, Larry.
All right.
This is pointless.
Ok?
It's time for plan "b."
You might want to watch out
that front window, Larry.
Son, this is what happens
when you fuck a stranger
in the ass!
Little language problem
here.
The little prick's
stonewalling me.
Walter!
What--what are you doing,
man?
What are you doing?
Here you go, Larry.
You see what happens?
You see what happens,
Larry?
You see what happens?
This is what happens
when you fuck a stranger
in the ass, Larry!
This is what happens,
Larry!
You see what happens,
Larry?
You see what happens
when you fuck a stranger
in the ass?
This is what happens.
You see what happens,
Larry?
Do you see what happens,
Larry,
when you fuck a stranger
in the ass?
This is what happens,
Larry!
Man: No!
This is what happens,
Larry!
This is what happens
when you fuck a stranger--
What the fuck
are you doing, man?!
Stop it!
I just bought
that fucking car last week!
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
I'm gonna
fuckin' kill you!
I just bought
the fucking car last week!
I’ll kill your
fucking car, man!
No! No! Hey! Hey!
That's not his--hey!
God damn it!
No! Oh, no!
Man: Fuck you!
You like that?
Fuck you!
I kill your fucking car!
I accept your apology.
No. I just--I just
Want to handle it
by myself from now on.
No, no, no.
That has nothing
to do with it.
Yes, the car made it home.
You're calling me at home.
No, Walter,
it did not look like...
Larry was about to crack.
Well,
that's your perception.
You know, Walter,
you're right.
There is
an unspoken message here.
It's fuck you!
Leave me the fuck alone!
Yeah, I’ll be at practice.
Pin your diapers on,
Lebowski.
Jackie Treehorn
wants to see you.
Jackie Treehorn knows
which Lebowski you are.
Jackie Treehorn wants to see
the deadbeat Lebowski.
You're not dealing
with morons here.
Hello, Dude.
Thanks for coming.
I'm Jackie Treehorn.
This is quite a pad
you got here, man.
Completely unspoiled.
What's your drink, Dude?
White Russian.
Thanks.
How's the smut business,
Jackie?
I wouldn't know,
Dude.
I deal in publishing,
entertainment,
political advocacy.
Oh. Which one's
Logjamming?
Yes, regrettably,
it's true.
Standards have fallen
in adult entertainment.
It's video, Dude.
Now that we're competing
with those amateurs,
We can't afford to invest
in little extras, like story,
production value,
feelings.
You know, people forget
that the brain is
the biggest erogenous zone.
On you maybe.
Of course, you have to take
the good with the bad.
New technology permits us
to do very exciting things
In interactive
erotic software.
Wave of the future,
Dude.
100% electronic.
Hmm. Well...
I still jerk off
manually.
Of course you do.
I can see you're anxious
for me to get to the point.
Well, here it is, Dude.
Where's Bunny?
Well, I thought you
might know that, man.
Why would I?
She only ran off
to get away from that
rather sizable debt to me.
No. She didn't run off.
She's been, um--
I've heard that kidnapping
story, so save it.
I know you're mixed up
in all this, Dude,
And I don't care what you're
trying to get from the husband.
That's your business.
All I’m saying is...
I want mine.
Yeah, right, man.
I mean, there are
a lot of, um,
Facets to this, a lot
of interested parties.
Excuse me.
Yeah?
Oh, yeah.
Where's that?
All right.
Excuse me.
Oh.
Forgive me.
No problemo, man.
So, uh...
If I, uh, can find
your money...
Uh, what's in it
for The Dude?
Well, of course,
there's that to discuss.
Uh, refill?
Yeah. The pope
shit in the woods?
10% finder's fee.
That all right?
Mmm. Ok.
Done, Jackie.
Yeah. I dig the way
you do business, man.
Your money
is being held
By a kid named
Larry Sellers.
He lives
in north Hollywood,
On Radford, uh...
By the
in-n-out burger.
A fuckin' brat,
but I’m sure your goons
Can get it off him.
I mean, he's 15.
Flunking social studies.
So, if you could just,
uh...
Write me a check for my
10% of half a million...
5 grand...
I’ll go out and mingle--
You mix a hell
of a Caucasian, Jackie.
A 15-year-old kid.
Is this
some sort of a joke?
No, no joke.
No funny stuff, Jackie.
the kid's got it.
Hi, fellas.
The kid just wanted
a car.
All The Dude ever wanted
was his rug back.
I'm not greedy.
It would really...
Tie the room together.
The stranger:
Darkness washed over The Dude.
Darker than
a black steer's took us
On a moonless prairie night.
There was no bottom.
# Yeah, yeah #
# Oh, yeah #
# What condition
my condition was in #
# I woke up this morning
with the sun down #
# Shinin' in him #
# I found my mind
in a brown paper bag #
# But then #
# I tripped on a cloud
and fell 8 miles high #
# I tore my mind
on a jagged sky #
# I just dropped in #
# To see what condition
my condition was in #
# Yeah, yeah, oh, yeah #
# What condition
my condition was in #
# I pushed my soul
in a deep dark hole #
# And then
I followed it in #
# I watched myself
crawlin' out #
# As I was crawlin' in #
# I got up so tight #
# I couldn't unwind #
# I saw so much #
# I broke my mind #
# I just dropped in #
# To see what condition
my condition was in #
# Yeah, yeah, oh, yeah #
# What condition
my condition was in #
# Someone
painted echoes on #
# In big black letters #
# On the dead inside #
# I kept my foot
on the gas #
# As I left the road #
# Blew out my mind #
# 8 miles out of Memphis,
and I got no spare #
# 8 miles straightened up
downtown somewhere #
# I just dropped in #
# To see what condition
my condition was in #
# I said,
I just dropped in #
# To see what condition
my condition was in #
# Yeah #
# Oh, yeah #
Ah...
But the charge was true
and they say
he ran away
branded!
Is this your only I.D.?
I know my rights,
man.
You don't know shit,
Lebowski.
I want
a fucking lawyer, man.
I want...
Bill Kunstler, man.
Or Ron Coobie.
Mr. Treehorn tells us
that he had to eject you
from his garden party,
that you were drunk
and abusive.
Mr. Treehorn treats objects
like women, man.
Mr. Treehorn draws
a lot of water in this town.
You don't draw shit,
Lebowski.
Now we got a nice quiet
little beach community here,
and I aim to keep it
nice and quiet.
So let me
make something plain.
I don't like you
sucking around,
bothering our citizens,
Lebowski.
I don't like
your jerk-off name,
your jerk-off face,
I don't like
your jerk-off behavior,
And I don't like you...
Jerk-off.
Do I make myself clear?
I'm sorry.
I wasn't listening.
Ow!
Fucking fascist!
Aah!
Stay out of Malibu,
Lebowski!
Ow!
Stay out of Malibu,
deadbeat!
Keep your ugly fucking
gold-bricking ass
out of
my beach community.
# I want to sleep with you
in the desert tonight #
# With a billion stars
all around #
Jesus...
Man, could you
change the channel?
Fuck you, man!
if you don't like my music,
get your own fucking cab!
I had a really rough--
I’ll pull over
and kiss your ass out.
Man, come on,
I had a rough night,
And I hate
the fucking eagles, man.
Out of my fucking cab!
Out! Get--
Hey...
Man!
Man, hey!
# Devil-may-care #
# And I’m the devil
with love to spare #
# So viva, Las Vegas #
# Viva, Las Vegas #
Oh...
Jesus.
Jeffrey.
Maude?
Love me.
Uh, that's my robe.
Maude: Tell me about
yourself, Jeffrey.
Well, not much
to tell.
I, um, I was one
of the authors
of the port Huron
Statement.
The original
Port Huron Statement.
Uh-huh.
Not the compromised
second draft.
Uh, and then I, uh,
you ever hear
of the Seattle 7?
Mmm.
That was me.
And, um,
the 6 other guys.
Um, and then
a music business briefly.
Oh?
Yeah, a roadie
for Metallica.
Oh.
Speed of sound tour.
Mm-hmm.
Bunch of assholes.
Uh, and then,
you know,
A little of this,
a little of that.
My career's slowed down
a little lately.
What do you do
for recreation?
Oh, the usual.
Bowl, drive around.
The occasional
acid flashback.
What happened
to your house?
Oh, Jackie Treehorn
trashed the place.
He thought I had
your father's money.
He got me out of the way
while he looked for it.
Cocktail?
No, thanks.
It's not my
father's money.
It's the
Foundation's.
Why did he think
you have it?
And who does?
Oh, Larry Sellers,
this high school kid.
Real fucking brat.
You know, this is a very
complicated case, Maude.
Lotta ins, lotta outs.
You know, fortunately,
I'm adhering to
a pretty strict, uh,
drug regiment to keep
my mind, you know,
Uh, limber, you know.
Very fucking close
to your father's money.
I keep telling you it's
the Foundation's money.
Father doesn't have any.
What are you talking about?
he's fucking loaded.
No, no, the wealth
was all mother's.
No, he runs stuff, uh--
We did let him run one
of the companies briefly,
But he didn't do
very well at it.
No, he's, you know.
No, he helps administer
the charities now,
and I give him
a reasonable allowance.
He has no money
of his own.
I know how he likes
to present himself.
Father's weakness
is vanity.
Hence, the slut.
Uh, do you think he, uh--
What is that, yoga?
It increases the chances
of conception.
Increases?
Well, yes.
What did you think
this was all about?
Fun and games?
I want a child.
Ok, yeah, ok,
but let me--
Ahem, let me explain
something about The Dude.
Uh, look, Jeffrey,
I don't want
a partner.
In fact, I don't
want the father
to be someone
I have to see socially
or who'll have
any interest
in raising
the child himself.
Oh, so that doctor--
Exactly. Now, what
happened to your face?
Did Jackie Treehorn
Do that as well?
No, uh, it was the chief
of police of Malibu.
A real reactionary.
So, your father...
Oh, yeah, I get it.
Yeah, yeah.
What?
Oh, man, my thinking
about this case
had become very uptight.
Yeah, your father.
Jeffrey, what are
you talking about?
Jeffrey!
Walter, if you're there,
pick up the fucking phone,
man, come on, Walter.
Pick it up, man,
this is an emergency.
Come on, enough--Dude?
Yeah, listen, Walter,
I'm at my place.
I need you to come
pick me up.
I can't drive, Dude,
It's Erev Shabbos.
What?
Erev Shabbos.
I can't drive.
Man!
I'm not even supposed
to pick up the phone
unless it's
an emergency.
This is
a fucking emergency.
I understand. That's why
I picked up the phone.
Walter, you fuck,
we gotta go
to Pasadena, man.
Come pick me up or I’m off
the fucking bowling team.
Get out of that
fucking car, man.
fucking car!
Get the fuck out
of the car, man.
Get out of
the fucking--
Who the fuck
are you, man?
Easy, man.
Relax, man.
No physical harm
intended.
Who the fuck
are you?
Why are you
following me around?
Come on, fuckhead.
Relax, man.
I'm a brother Seamus.
Brother Seamus?
Like an Irish monk?
What the fuck are you
talking about?
My name is Da Fino.
I'm a private snoop,
like you, man.
What?
A dick, man.
And let me tell you
something. I dig your work.
Playing one side
against the other.
In bed with everybody.
Fabulous stuff, man.
I'm not--fuck it, man.
Just stay away from
my fucking lady friend.
Hey, hey, I’m not messing
with your special lady.
She's not
my special lady.
She's my fucking
lady friend.
I'm just helping
her conceive, man.
Hey, man, I’m not--
Who are you
working for?
Lebowski?
Jackie Treehorn?
The Knutsens.
The--who the fuck
are the Knutsens?
The Knutsen's. It's
a wandering daughter job.
Bunny Lebowski, man.
Her real name
is Fawn Knutsen.
Her parents want her back.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Crazy, huh? Ran away
about a year ago.
The Knutsens told me
I should show her this
when I found her.
It's the family farm.
It's outside of
Moorhead, Minnesota.
They think it'll
make her homesick.
Oh, boy.
How are you gonna
keep 'em
down on the farm
once they've seen
Karl Hungus?
She's been
kidnapped, Da Fino.
Oh, man.
Oh, I don't know.
maybe not,
But she's definitely
not around.
Hey, maybe you and me
could pool our resources.
Trade information.
Professional courtesy.
Compeers, you know
what I mean?
Yeah, yeah, I get it.
Fuck off, Da Fino.
And stay away
from my special--
From my fucking
lady friend, man.
Ze lingonberry
pancakes.
Lingonberry pancakes.
Sree pigs in blanket.
Dieter: Huh?
She has lingonberry
pancakes.
I mean we totally
fucked it up, man.
We fucked up his payoff,
we got the kidnappers
all pissed off,
And Lebowski, you know,
he yelled at me a lot,
But he didn't
do anything, huh?
Well, sometimes
it's a cathartic--
No, no, I’m saying if
he knows I’m a fuck-up,
why does he
leave me in charge
Of getting his wife back?
Because he doesn't fucking
want her back, man.
He's had enough.
He no longer digs her.
It's all a show.
Ok, but then, why
doesn't he give a shit
About his million bucks?
I mean, he knows we never
handed off his briefcase,
but he never asked
for it back.
The million bucks was
never in the briefcase.
The briefcase was
fucking empty, man.
The asshole was hoping
that they would kill her.
You threw out a ringer
for a ringer.
Ok, but how does
this all add up
To an emergency?
Huh?
I'm saying I see what
you're getting at, Dude,
He kept the money.
My point is, ahem,
here we are,
it's Shabbos,
the Sabbath, which
I'm allowed to break
only if it's a matter
of life or death.
Will you come off it,
Walter?
You're not even
fucking Jewish, man.
What the fuck are
you talking about?
You're fucking
Polish-catholic.
What the fuck are
you talking about?
I converted when
I married Cynthia.
Come on, Dude.
Yeah, yeah.
You know this.
And 5 fucking years ago,
you were divorced.
So what are saying?
When you get divorced,
You turn in
your library card?
You get a new license?
You stop being Jewish?
This is
the driveway, huh?
I'm Jewish as
fucking Tevye.
Man, you know,
it's all a part
of your sick
Cynthia thing.
Man, taking care
of her fucking dog.
Going to her
fucking synagogue.
You're living in
the fucking past.
3,000 years of
beautiful tradition
from Moses
to Sandy Koufax,
you're goddamn right
I'm living in
the fucking past!
I--Jesus.
What the hell
happened?
# Viva Las Vegas #
Ah!
Where was she, man?
Visiting friends of hers
in palm springs.
She just picked up
and left.
Never bothered
to tell us.
Well, I guess the fucking
nihilist knew where she was.
Jesus, Dude, she never
even kidnapped herself.
Who is this gentleman,
Dude?
Who am I? I'm
a fucking veteran.
He shouldn't go
in there, Dude.
He's very angry.
Hello, man.
So, she's back,
no thanks to you.
Where's the fucking
money, Lebowski?
A million bucks
from fucking needy
Little urban
achievers!
You are scum, man!
Who the hell is he?
Who am I? Who am I?
I'm the guy
that's gonna kick
Your phony goldbricking
ass! That's who I am.
Man, we know the briefcase
was fucking empty.
We know you kept the million
bucks for yourself.
You have your story,
I have mine.
I say I entrusted
the money to you,
And you stole it.
As if we would ever
dream of taking
your bullshit
money!
You thought that Bunny
had been kidnapped,
and you were
fucking glad, man.
You could use it as an excuse
to make some money disappear.
All you needed was a sap
to pin it on.
You just met me.
You--human paraquat!
You figured, oh,
here's a loser, you know.
A deadbeat.
somebody the square community
Won't give a shit about.
Well, aren't you?
Well, yeah, but--
Get out, both of you.
Look at that
fucking phony, Dude.
Pretending to be a
fucking millionaire.
Out of this house now,
you bums!
Let me tell you
something else.
I've seen a lot of
spinals, Dude,
And this guy's
a fake.
A fucking
goldbricker.
Stay away from me,
mister!
This guy
fucking walks.
I've never been
more certain
of anything
in my life.
You stay away from me!
Walter, for Christ’s sake,
man, he's a cripple.
Come on, come on.
Get away from me!
Aah!
Put him down, man!
Yeah, I’ll put
him down, Dude!
Rauss! Achtung, baby!
Come on, man, help me
put him back in his chair.
Sure, you'll see
some tank battles.
But fighting in desert
is very different
from fighting
in canopy jungle.
I mean 'nam was
a foot soldier's war.
Whereas, this thing
should, uh, you know,
should be
a piece of cake.
I mean, I had
an M16, Jacko.
Not an Abrams
fucking tank.
Me and Charlie,
eyeball to eyeball.
Yeah.
That's fuckin' combat.
The man in the
black pajamas, Dude.
Worthy fuckin'
adversary.
Who's in
pajamas, Walter?
Shut the fuck up,
Donny.
Whereas, what we
have here...
Lots of fig-eaters wearing
towels on their heads,
trying to find reverse
on a soviet tank.
This--this is not
a worthy--
Hey!
What's this
day of rest shit?
What's this bullshit!
I don't fuckin' care!
It don't matter
to Jesus.
But you not
fooling me, man.
You might fool the fucks
in the league office,
but you don't
fool Jesus.
It's bush league
psyche-out stuff.
Laughable, man. Ha ha!
I would have fucked you
in the ass Saturday.
I’ll fuck you in the ass
Next Wednesday instead.
Whoo! You got a date
Wednesday, baby.
He's cracking.
The whole concept of Asia.
I mean, many learned men
have disputed this,
but in the 14th century.
the rabahm, he--
Well, they
finally did it.
They killed
my fucking car.
We want some money,
Lebowski.
Ja, otherwise,
we kill the girl.
Ja, it seems
you have forgotten
Our little deal,
Lebowski.
You don't have the
fucking girl, dipshit.
We know you never did.
Are these the Nazis,
Walter?
No, Donny, these men
are nihilists.
There's nothing
to be afraid of.
Vee don't care. Vee
still want the money,
Lebowski, or
we'll fuck you up.
Fuck you.
Fuck the 3 of yous.
No, without a hostage,
there is no ransom.
That's what ransom is.
Those are the fucking rules.
His girlfriend
gave up her toe.
She zought we'd be
getting $1 million.
It's not fair.
Fair? Who's the fucking
nihilist around here?
You bunch of
fucking crybabies.
Cool it, Walter.
Hey, look, pal,
There never was
any money.
The big Lebowski gave
me an empty briefcase,
So take it up
with him, man.
Yeah, and I would like
my undies back.
Are these guys gonna
hurt us, Walter?
No, Donny, these
men are cowards.
Ok, so we take ze
money you haf on you
And we calls it
even.
Fuck you.
Hey, no, come on,
Walter, come on.
We're ending this
thing cheap, man.
No, what's mine is mine.
Oh, come on, Walter.
Dieter:
No funny stuff.
All right,
all right, I got,
Uh, 4 bucks,
almost 5.
I got $18.
Walter: What's
mine is mine.
We fuck you up, man.
We takes the money.
Come and get it.
Dieter: We fuck you up.
Show me what
you got, nihilist.
I fuck you.
Walter, come on,
he's got a sword.
Fucking dipshit with
a 9-toed woman.
Fuck you!
I fuck you up!
Take it easy, man.
Here's the $4.00.
I got a fucking ball, man.
Aah!
Anti-semite!
I fuck you in ze ass.
I fuck you
in ze ass.
I fuck you!
We got a man down, Dude.
God, they shot him,
man.
No, Dude.
They shot Donny?
There weren't
any shots fired.
Huh?
It's a heart attack.
Call the medics, Dude.
I'd go myself, but I’m
pumping blood. Might pass out.
Rest easy, good buddy,
you're doing fine.
We got help
choppering in.
Hello, gentlemen.
You are the bereaved?
Yeah, man.
Francis Donnelly.
Pleased to meet you.
Jeff Lebowski.
Walter Sobchak.
The Dude, actually,
is, uh--
Excuse me?
Oh, nothing.
Yes, I understand you're
taking away the remains.
Yeah.
We have the urn.
I assume this is
credit card.
Yeah.
Walter: Ahem.
What's this?
That's for the urn.
Don't need it. We're
Scattering the ashes.
Yes, so we
Were informed.
However, we must,
Of course,
Transmit the remains
To you in a receptacle.
This is $180.
It is our most modestly
priced receptacle.
Can we just, uh--$180?
They range up to 3,000.
Uh, we're, uh, ahem!
Can't we just
rent it from you?
Sir, this is a mortuary,
not a rental house.
We're scattering
the fucking ashes!
Look, just because
we're bereaved,
Doesn't
make us saps!
Sir, please,
lower your voices.
Man, don't you have,
you know,
Something else we could
put him in, you know?
That is our most modestly
priced receptacle.
God damn it!
Is there a Ralph’s
around here?
Donny was
a good bowler
And a good man.
He was one of us.
He was a man who loved
the outdoors and bowling.
And as a surfer,
he explored the beaches
of Southern California,
from La Jolla
to Leo Carrillo
and up to Pismo.
He died--he died as so
many men of his generation,
Before his time.
In your wisdom, Lord,
you took him.
As you took so many bright,
flowering young men
at Khe Sanh, at Lan Doc,
and Hill 364.
These young men
gave their lives.
So did Donny.
Donny who loved bowling.
And so, Theodore
Donald Karabatsos,
in accordance with
what we think
your dying wishes
might well have been,
We commit your final
mortal remains
To the bosom
of the pacific ocean,
which you loved so well.
Good night, sweet prince.
Shit.
Oh, shit, Dude,
I'm sorry.
God damn wind.
God damn it, Walter.
You fucking asshole!
Dude, I’m sorry.
Everything's a fucking
travesty with you, man.
I'm sorry.
It was an accident.
What was that shit
About Vietnam?
What the fuck
does anything
have to do
with Vietnam?
What the fuck are
you talking about?
Dude, I’m sorry.
Fuckin'...
Fuck, Walter.
Come on, Dude.
Hey, fuck it, man.
Let's go bowling.
And when you're
sitting there
in your silk
upholstered chair
talkin' to some rich folks
that you know
well, I hope
you don't see me
in my ragged company
Aw, that you know
I could never be alone
2 oat sodas, Gary.
Good luck tomorrow.
Yeah, thanks, man.
I'm sorry to hear
about Donny.
Oh, well, yeah,
you know,
Sometimes you
eat the bar,
And sometimes,
you know--
Hey, man!
Howdy doo, Dude.
I wondered if I’d
see you again.
I wouldn't
miss the semis?
How have things
been going?
Oh, you know,
strikes and gutters,
ups and downs.
Sure. I gotcha.
Yeah. Thanks, Gary.
Well, take care, man.
Gotta get back.
Sure. Take it
easy, Dude.
Oh, yeah.
I know that you will.
Yeah, well,
The Dude abides.
I don't know about you,
but I take comfort in that.
It's good knowing he's
out there, The Dude.
Takin' her easy
for all us sinners.
Shoosh. I sure hope
he makes the finals.
Well, that about does her.
Wraps her all up.
Things seemed to have
worked out pretty good
for The Dude and Walter.
And it was
a pretty good story,
Don't you think?
Made me laugh
to beat the band.
Parts, anyway.
I didn't like
seeing Donny go.
But then
I happen to know
That there's a little
Lebowski on the way.
I guess that's how the
whole darn human comedy
keeps perpetuating itself
down through
the generations.
westward in the wagons,
and across the sands
of time until we--
Oh, look at me.
I'm ramblin' again.
Well, I hope you folks
enjoyed yourselves.
Catch ya later
on down the trail.
Say, friend,
you got any more
of that goodSarsaparilla?
www.moviesubtitles.org